<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Duco Veen</title>
    <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication_types/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.ducoveen.com/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.ducoveen.com/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication_types/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian statistics and modelling</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_bayesian_statistics_and_modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_bayesian_statistics_and_modelling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayesian statistics is an approach to data analysis based on Bayes&#39; theorem, where available knowledge about parameters in a statistical model is updated with the information in observed data. The background knowledge is expressed as a prior distribution and combined with observational data in the form of a likelihood function to determine the posterior distribution. The posterior can also be used for making predictions about future events. This Primer describes the stages involved in Bayesian analysis, from specifying the prior and data models to deriving inference, model checking and refinement. We discuss the importance of prior and posterior predictive checking, selecting a proper technique for sampling from a posterior distribution, variational inference and variable selection. Examples of successful applications of Bayesian analysis across various research fields are provided, including in social sciences, ecology, genetics, medicine and more. We propose strategies for reproducibility and reporting standards, outlining an updated WAMBS (when to Worry and how to Avoid the Misuse of Bayesian Statistics) checklist. Finally, we outline the impact of Bayesian analysis on artificial intelligence, a major goal in the next decade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A prospective, randomized, single-blinded, crossover trial to investigate the effect of a wearable device in addition to a daily symptom diary for the remote early detection of SARS-CoV-2 infections (COVID-RED)</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_covid_red_protocol/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_covid_red_protocol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is currently thought that most—but not all—individuals infected with SARS-CoV-2 develop symptoms, but that the infectious period starts on average two days before the first overt symptoms appear. It is estimated that pre- and asymptomatic individuals are responsible for more than half of all transmissions. By detecting infected individuals before they have overt symptoms, wearable devices could potentially and significantly reduce the proportion of transmissions by pre-symptomatic individuals. Using laboratory-confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infections (detected via serology tests [to determine if there are antibodies against the SARS-CoV-2 in the blood] or SARS-CoV-2 infection tests such as polymerase chain reaction [PCR] or antigen tests) as the gold standard, we will determine the sensitivity, specificity, positive predictive value (PPV) and negative predictive value (NPV) for the following two algorithms to detect first time SARS-CoV-2 infection including early or asymptomatic infection. The algorithm using Ava bracelet data when coupled with self-reported Daily Symptom Diary data (Wearable + Symptom Data Algo; experimental condition) the algorithm using self-reported Daily Symptom Diary data alone (Symptom Only Algo; control condition) In addition, we will determine which of the two algorithms has superior performance characteristics for detecting SARS-CoV-2 infection including early or asymptomatic infection as confirmed by SARS-CoV-2 virus testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Linear Randomized Response Modeling using GLMMRR</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_glmmrr_software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_glmmrr_software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Randomized response (RR) designs are used to collect response data about sensitive behaviors (e.g., criminal behavior, sexual desires). The modeling of RR data is more complex, since it requires a description of the RR process. For the class of generalized linear mixed models (GLMMs), the RR process can be represented by an adjusted link function, which relates the expected RR to the linear predictor, for most common RR designs. The package GLMMRR includes modified link functions for four different cumulative distributions (i.e., logistic, cumulative normal, gumbel, cauchy) for GLMs and GLMMs, where the package lme4 facilitates ML and REML estimation. The mixed modeling framework in GLMMRR can be used to jointly analyse data collected under different designs (e.g., dual questioning, multilevel, mixed mode, repeated measurements designs, multiple-group designs). The well-known features of the GLM and GLMM (package lme4) software are remained, while adding new model-fit tests, residual analyses, and plot functions to give support to a profound RR data analysis. Data of Hoglinger and Jann (2018) and Hoglinger, Jann, and Diekmann (2014) is used
to illustrate the methodology and software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speech discrimination in infants at family risk of dyslexia. Group and individual-based analyses</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_speech-discrimination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_speech-discrimination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deficiencies in discriminating and identifying speech sounds have been widely attested in individuals with dyslexia as well as in young children at family risk (FR) of dyslexia. A speech perception deficit has been hypothesized to be causally related to reading and spelling difficulties. So far, however, early speech perception of FR infants has not been assessed at different ages within a single experimental design. Furthermore, a combination of group- and individual-based analyses has not been made. In this cross-sectional study, vowel discrimination of 6-, 8-, and 10-month-old Dutch FR infants and their nonrisk (no-FR) peers was assessed. Infants (N = 196) were tested on a native English /aː/–/eː/ and non-native English /ɛ/–/æ/ contrast using a hybrid visual habituation paradigm. Frequentist analyses were used to interpret group differences. Bayesian hierarchical modeling was used to classify individuals as speech sound discriminators. FR and no-FR infants discriminated the native contrast at all ages. However, individual classification of the no-FR infants suggests improved discrimination with age, but not for the FR infants. No-FR infants discriminated the non-native contrast at 6 and 10 months, but not at 8 months. FR infants did not show evidence of discriminating the contrast at any of the ages, with 0% being classified as discriminators. The group- and individual-based data are complementary and together point toward speech perception differences between the groups. The findings also indicate that conducting individual analyses on hybrid visual habituation outcomes is possible. These outcomes form a fruitful avenue for gaining more understanding of development, group differences, and prospective relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematically Defined Informative Priors in Bayesian Estimation. An Empirical Application on the Transmission of Internalizing Symptoms Through Mother-Adolescent Interaction Behavior</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_systematically_defined_informative_priors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/2021_systematically_defined_informative_priors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background&lt;/strong&gt;
Bayesian estimation with informative priors permits updating previous findings with new data, thus generating cumulative knowledge. To reduce subjectivity in the process, the present study emphasizes how to systematically weigh and specify informative priors and highlights the use of different aggregation methods using an empirical example that examined whether observed mother-adolescent positive and negative interaction behavior mediate the associations between maternal and adolescent internalizing symptoms ac ross early to mid-adolescence in a 3-year longitudinal multi-method design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods&lt;/strong&gt;
The sample consisted of 102 mother-adolescent dyads (39.2% girls, Mage T1 = 13.0). Mothers and adolescents reported on their internalizing symptoms and their interaction behaviors were observed during a conflict task. We systematically searched for previous studies and used an expert-informed weighting system to account for their relevance. Subsequently, we aggregated the (power) priors using three methods: linear pooling, logarithmic pooling, and fitting a normal distribution to the linear pool by means of maximum likelihood estimation. We compared the impact of the three differently specified informative priors and default priors on the prior predictive distribution, shrinkage, and the posterior estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;
The prior predictive distributions for the three informative priors were quite similar and centered around the observed data mean. The shrinkage results showed that the logarithmic pooled priors were least affected by the data. Most posterior estimates were similar across the different priors. Some previous studies contained extremely specific information, resulting in bimodal posterior distributions for the analyses with linear pooled prior distributions. The posteriors following the fitted normal priors and default priors were very similar. Overall, we found that maternal, but not adolescent, internalizing symptoms predicted subsequent mother-adolescent interaction behavior, whereas negative interaction behavior seemed to predict subsequent internalizing symptoms. Evidence regarding mediation effects remained limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
A systematic search for previous information and an expert-built weighting system contribute to a clear specification of power priors. How information from multiple previous studies should be included in the prior depends on theoretical considerations (e.g., the prior is an updated Bayesian distribution), and may also be affected by pragmatic considerations regarding the impact of the previous results at hand (e.g., extremely specific previous results).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A step forward. Bayesian hierarchical modelling as a tool in assessment of individual discrimination performance</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/a-step-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/a-step-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standard Errors, Priors, and Bridge Sampling. A Discussion of Liu et al.</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/discussion-of-liu-et-al/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/discussion-of-liu-et-al/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta analysis of the outcomes of treatment of internal carotid artery near occlusion</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/meta-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/meta-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generalized Linear Mixed Models for Randomized Responses</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/glmmrr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/glmmrr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Data Agreement Criterion to Rank Experts&#39; Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/dac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/dac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proposal for a Five-Step Method to Elicit Expert Judgment</title>
      <link>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/five-step-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ducoveen.com/publication/five-step-method/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
